Feng Sir,
冯科长
we offer you
我们想再最后
one last chance,
给你一次机会
to talk with us.
跟我们谈谈
What's there to talk about?
有什么可谈的
I know Tan Shiyuan and my brother
我知道谭施远和我哥哥
are smuggling military supplies
在跟里见直树
with Nakamura Naoki,
走私军需品
and I know
我也知道
you're not the one
掌控这批货物的人
behind the deal.
不是你
We suggest
我们是想劝你
not to make scapegoat
不要在这个时候
of Tan Shiyuan.
成为谭施远的挡箭牌
Get to the point.
直说吧
What do you want?
你们要什么
The manifest
货单
and the pass.
通行证
If I
这两样东西
gave you those,
我如果给你们
I'd have
我就没有
no leverage left.
任何翻身的资本了
But,
可问题是
even if you don't,
就算你不给
you already
现在你也没有
have no leverage.
任何翻身的资本
If you just want
既然你们只想要
the pass and the manifest,
通行证跟货单
just kill me.
杀了我就行
I have a deal for you.
我们想跟你合作
In other words,
换句话说
we offer you help.
我们是在帮你
Help?
帮我
If the information is correct,
如果消息没有错的话
you've been suspended
你应该是被谭施远
by Tan Shiyuan.
停职了
Not cooperating with us could be
你不跟我们合作的话
very dangerous for you.
会很危险
Knowing Tan Shiyuan as I do,
以我对谭施远的了解
the suspension is just a smokescreen.
停职只是幌子
If you got out of the car now,
你如果现在下车的话
two things could happen:
会有两种可能性
one,
一
he pins
他把走私这条线
the smuggling totally on you,
彻头彻尾地推到你身上
and you take the fall;
你替他掉脑袋
two,
二
you might not make it home
你还没有到家
because you would die
就有可能因为某个事故
in an "accident."
死在街上
Of course,
当然
there's a third option,
还有第三种可能性
you do nothing,
你什么都不做
but we still
但是我们仍然有
have countless ways
无数的方法
to expose your crimes.
可以揭露你们的罪行
Not only you and Tan Shiyuan
不仅你和谭施远
would be punished,
会受到制裁
but you'd also be despised
往后的日子里
by every Chinese,
你会被每一个国人唾弃
branded as a traitor
永远会被骂
and a lapdog for the Japanese.
是日本人的汉奸走狗
What do you propose?
你们想怎么合作
Hand over the pass and the manifest,
交出通行证和货单
and tell us everything
把你知道的真相
you know.
都说出来
And,
同时
declare that the warrant for Chen Hao's
针对陈浩的凶案通缉
supposed murder is fabricated
证实是捏造的
and cancel the warrant.
取消通缉
What do I get out of this?
我能得到什么
A chance to live.
活着的机会
I have one condition:
我有个条件
I must leave Shanghai
我必须离开上海
and get away from Tan Shiyuan's influence.
脱离谭施远的势力范围
I can arrange for you to go to Nanjing
我可以让你去南京
and be investigated
在南京的警察系统里
by the police there.
接受调查
One for each of us,
一人一张
to ensure it's secure.
确保安全
I'll wait for your message.
我等你们消息
You go first!
你先走
I'll cover you!
我掩护你
What about you?
你怎么办
Let's go together!
一起走
The evidence is crucial.
证据重要
Meet at the civilian house.
我们民居见
Okay,
好
see you there.
民居见
Catch that person!
把那人抓回来
Yes, Sir.
是
Hello?
喂
[Mr. Nakamura,]
里见先生
[the pass]
出港通行证
has been secured,
已经拿下来了
and the Shinei Maru
新荣丸号
can set sail tomorrow.
明天就可以出发
There must be no more mistakes.
不要再有任何的差错
Anything else?
还有什么事
Deputy Director Tan,
谭副局长
there was a shootout at Sanyang Fisheries.
三洋水产发生枪战
Feng Guangyun is killed,
冯广云被杀
and Hua Zhen was taken.
华桢被人带走了
Who took him?
对方是谁
It seems to be the Reviving Society.
好像是复兴社的
It looks like
看样子
Hua's family is handling
是华家派出的势力
their internal affairs.
在处理他们的家事
We should just watch
我们派人静观其变就好
and stay out of it.
什么都不用管
Did you put protesters
新荣丸号附近闹事的
against Shinei Maru under arrest?
都抓起来了吗
Someone protected the organizers
有人把组织闹事的人
and gathered them all
全都圈在中间
in the middle of the crowd.
保护起来了
Deputy Director Tan,
谭副局长
what should we do now?
我们现在怎么办
If we make arrests by force,
如果要抓人
it will definitely lead to a bloody conflict.
肯定会导致流血冲突
Are you suggesting we wait?
不抓还围起来看戏吗
If the Shinei Maru
如果新荣丸号
doesn't leave the port,
没能顺利离港
we're all finished.
我们都得完蛋
Understood.
是
[I'm meeting with you now]
这时候跟你见面
[to pass an important]
是因为有重要消息
[information.]
要跟你传达
[We've learned]
组织得知
[that there are agents from the Reviving Society]
法租界的安琪啤酒公司
[at the A.G. Beer in the French Concession.]
一直有复兴社特务活动
[It's a critical moment to prevent]
现在正是阻止新荣丸号
[the Shinei Maru from leaving port.]
离港的关键时刻
[You must ensure our actions]
你要确保我们的行动
[are not disrupted by them.]
不要被他们干扰
I had a suspicion of this.
这件事我有所察觉
[After Wei Daiqing went after me,]
魏岱擎盯上我之后
[I discreetly investigated]
我就悄悄调查了
[the background of A.G. Beer]
安琪啤酒公司的背景
[and found their inquiry]
发现他们调查
[seemed focused solely on Hua Zhen]
似乎只围绕华桢展开
[and was different]
且行事风格
[from the usual actions]
与以往的复兴社
[of the Reviving Society.]
并不相同
[I then used the Council's authority]
之后我用公董局的名义
[to access their rental information]
调取过他们的房租信息
[and confirmed that the tenant's identity]
查到承租人的身份
[is indeed connected to the Hua family.]
确实与华家有关
[This suggests]
这说明
[that the company might actually]
这家公司很有可能
[be Hua's own people]
是华家自己人
[investigating Hua Zhen's]
在调查华桢
[activities in Shanghai.]
在上海的行踪
When I discovered Hua Liang
然后我发现华梁
was in Shanghai,
果然就在上海
I directly contacted him.
便直接联系了他
Mr. Hua? You have a call.
华先生是吗 您电话
Hello?
喂
[Mr. Hua Liang,]
华梁先生
[the beer company you opened]
你在法租界
[in the French Concession,]
开的啤酒公司
[your brother doesn't know about it, right?]
你弟弟应该不知道吧
From his reaction,
从他的反应来看
I must have guessed right.
我应该猜对了
Once the facade is torn down,
一旦伪装被撕破
the dissolution of A.G. Beer
安琪啤酒公司
isn't far off.
离解散就不远了
We've arrived.
到了
[Your communist friends]
你的共产党朋友
[sure have a way of getting things done,]
还真是神通广大啊
[capable of reaching me by phone.]
电话都打到我这儿来了
[Well, it's good timing.]
不过也好
[It coincides with my quitting.]
现在收手
[I can stop, now]
我也不用
[playing games]
再跟那个魏岱擎
[with Wei Daiqing.]
玩儿过家家了
And this,
对了
isn't this the watch
这是我送你的
I gave you?
那块儿表吧
I remember
我记得这是你
I gave it to you
考上电雷学校的时候
when you got into S.M.C.
我送给你的礼物
I think it was
应该是你的
your first watch.
第一块儿手表
Feng Guangyun told me
冯广云跟我说
you pawned it
你为了给陈浩买药
to buy medicine for Chen Hao.
把它当给了药铺的老板
Next time, ask me for money
以后没钱找我要
instead of
不要随便
pawning things I gave you.
把我送给你的东西给人
This is Jin Qin.
金秦
You
你们应该
should have known him.
打过几次交道了吧
He was dad's bodyguard.
他是爸爸以前的警卫
Mr. Hua.
华先生
After Wei Daiqing
魏岱擎
was expelled from
被淞沪警备司令部
the Shanghai Garrison Command,
开除之后
the investigation against you
针对您的调查
never actually stopped.
其实一直没有终止
Mr. Hua arranged for him
华秘书安排他进特务处
to join the Secret Service
一方面是为了
to put him under control
控制他的行动
and
另一方面
to use him
也是利用他的行动
to eliminate any communists around you
消灭您身边的共产党
and destroy any evidence
销毁一切
that could be harmful to you.
不利于您的证据
You can treat
魏岱擎您可以
Wei Daiqing like a dog,
当他是一条狗
but Mr. Hua did all this
但华秘书做这一切
to protect you.
是为了保护您
Is Mrs. Ji
季太太
at your place?
在你那儿
I thought your primary concern right now
我以为你现在最关心的
would be this manifest.
是这张货物单呢
Let them release her.
叫他们把人放了
She's already dead.
她已经死了
What time is it?
现在几点了
Mom has been waiting for you to come home.
妈妈一直等着你回家呢
Come back to Nanjing with me.
跟我回南京
Mr. Hua,
华先生
please.
走吧
[Do you know]
华家做这种事
[how many people could get killed?]
你知道会害死多少人吗
What are you trying to do, exactly?
你到底想干什么
I'm asking you,
我问你话呢
I'm one of the company shareholders!
我就是公司的股东之一
I'm involved in this
我来干这些事情
because I have to!
是因为我不能不干
It's my duty!
这是我的职责
The cowards hiding in the shadows,
躲在背后的那帮王八蛋
do you need to know who they are?
你需要知道他们是谁吗
What difference does it make
你把这些事情搞清楚了
if you understand all this?
又能怎么样
Can you stop it?
你阻止得了吗
Even the Chairman
连高高在上的委员长
can not.
也不行
The world
这个世界
isn't black or white.
不是非黑即白
You want to change the world,
你想改变这个世界
but does the world
可是这个世界
need you to change it?
需要你来改变吗
Does it?
需要吗
It won't even allow you to change it.
它也容不得你来改变
Indeed, the world
这世界的确
isn't just black or white,
不是非黑即白
but there's always right or wrong.
但它始终也有是非对错
[Hua Zhen!]
华桢
[What are you doing, have you lost your mind?]
你干什么 你疯了
What's going on?
怎么回事儿
Are we under attack?
我们遭受袭击了
Who did it?
谁干的
The Communists?
共产党
What Communists?
什么共产党
The company has been dissolved.
公司解散了
Dissolved?
解散了
Where's Jin Qin?
金秦呢
Get Jin Qin here.
你把金秦叫来
I'll ask him directly!
我当面问他
Mr. Jin left yesterday.
金老板昨天已经走了
He left?
已经走了
Excuse me,
兄弟
why... why don't you
那 那你打个电话
call Mr. Yu
问问愚先生
and ask if he
你问问愚先生
knows about this?
知不知道这件事
Mr. Yu?
愚先生
Which Mr. Yu?
哪个愚先生
Our boss,
我们的老板
the one known as Mr. Yu...
大智若愚的愚
I don't know about this.
我不清楚啊
It's above your pay grade...
你层级不够
Excuse me, Mr. Wei,
对了 魏先生
I need you to
那个 你的车钥匙
return the car key.
需要先还给我
Above your pay grade...
层级不够
Mr. Wei?
魏先生
Above...
不够
Mr. Yu probably
愚先生可能
doesn't know about this.
不知道这事儿
Mr. Yu doesn't know.
愚先生不知道这事儿
You... stop moving things.
你 你别搬了
Stop...
别搬
Don't move...
别搬了
[Hurry up!]
快点
Just stop.
你别搬了
Hurry!
快搬
I'm begging you,
我求求你了
please stop!
不要再搬了
Who are you anyway?
你谁啊你
Who are you?
你是谁啊
I don't recognize you.
我没见过你啊
I'm the landlord. What's the issue?
我是房东 怎么了
Landlord?
房东
Yes,
对呀
Mr. Jin told me
金老板说了
he's taken
有用的东西
everything useful
他全搬走了
and left the rest
这剩下的东西
for me to handle.
全让我来处理
Sir,
大哥
did Mr. Jin tell you
那金老板有没有跟你说
how long he rented this place?
这房子他租多久
It's on a monthly basis.
论月租的
There are still a few days left this month,
这个月还差几天
and he suddenly asked me to take over.
突然让我来收房
That doesn't make sense.
没道理呀
That doesn't make any sense,
这没道理呀
sir!
大哥
Are you crazy?
你神经病吧你
You brat!
小赤佬
Come on, move it!
走 快搬
I'm not a brat!
我不是小赤佬
I,
我
am Wei Daiqing,
国民政府
the director of the Secret Service of the Reviving Society
复兴社特务处处长
under the National Government!
魏岱擎
Without my permission,
不经我的允许
none of you
你们谁也别想
can touch my things!
动我的东西
[He's lost it!]
这人疯了
It doesn't make any sense.
没有道理呀
Why is this happening?
这是为什么呢
Why?
为什么呢
[It's not over.]
没完
I still have leads!
我还有线索
Chen Hao!
陈浩
I'm okay.
我没事儿
What about Xiang Yuansheng?
向远生呢
Has he come back yet?
向远生回来了吗
He hasn't.
没回来
What happened exactly?
到底发生什么事情了
How did you end up like this?
你怎么弄成这样
Someone shot at us,
有人朝我们开枪
and Feng Guangyun is dead.
冯广云也死了
Xiang Yuansheng and I
我跟向远生约好
were supposed to meet here.
在这儿碰头的
Here's the pass.
这是通行证
The manifest is with Xiang Yuansheng.
货单在向远生那儿
You're badly hurt.
你现在伤得太严重了
I need to get you to a hospital first.
我先送你去医院
Forget about me,
别管我
go to the newspaper office.
你赶紧去报社
It's crucial
最重要的是
to expose the pass and the manifest.
曝光通行证跟货单
No,
不
we have to go together.
我们要一起走
I can't.
我走不动了
I really can't move.
我真的走不动了
The mission is what matters most.
最重要的是完成任务
This is our last chance.
这是最后的机会
Forget about me.
别管我
Mrs. Ji...
季
Mrs. Ji is gone.
季太太已经遇害了
We can't afford
我们小组的人
any more losses in our team.
不能再有任何差池
You... you wait here.
你 你在这儿等我
I'll contact our comrades
我马上联系同志
to get you out.
来转移你
Chen Hao,
陈浩
your new mission
你现在最新的任务
is to survive.
就是一定一定要活着
Hang in there.
坚持住
Alright,
好
I'll complete the mission.
我一定会完成好任务
Just go.
走啊
Dad,
爸
I'm stepping out.
我出去一趟
Where are you heading? Wait!
你去哪儿啊 等等
What are you up to?
你去干什么
Dad...
爸
I have to go.
我必须要去
No.
不行
Dad,
爸
they need me.
他们需要我
No.
不行
Wait for me.
你等等
Here.
来
I will wait for you at home.
爸在家等你
Sir,
老板
this car was repaired yesterday.
这车是昨天修的
We fixed bullet holes
修复了枪痕
and replaced two tires,
换了两条轮胎
that's all.
别的就没啥
I don't need this info right now!
我现在看这个没有用
I need to know
我要知道他们
where they went.
开车去哪儿了
How would I know that?
这我哪儿知道啊这
You must know at least
车往哪个方向走
the direction they headed!
你总知道吧
I... I only have
我 我只知道
a rough idea.
大概的方向
Fine!
好
We'll follow
那我们就按照
the tire tracks,
车辙的轨迹
road by road!
一条路一条路地找
Let's go!
走
Okay, okay.
好 好
Chen Hao!
陈浩
Mr. Hua,
姓华的
there's nothing left for you
现在你再没有什么
to argue about, is there?
可狡辩的了吧
Where is Chen Hao?
陈浩在哪儿
Still worried
还有闲心
about your Communist comrade?
关心你的共产党同党
I'm asking you where Chen Hao is.
我问你陈浩在哪儿
Admitting it, aren't you?
承认了吧
The one hiding in the false wall
上次在圣恩书店
at Shengen Book Store last time was him, right?
夹壁里藏着的就是他吧
You don't have
你可没有
his luck this time.
他那样的好运气了
No more
这一次
communist comrades
没有共产党同党
or Ms. bullshit Shi from bullshit Council
或者公董局的石小姐
to rescue you now.
来救你了
Do you know why you
你知道自己为什么
always lose?
总是输吗
I lost?
我输
Yes,
是
I've lost before.
我以前是输
And why?
我为什么输
Because our party state
是因为党国里
is filled with people like you
到处都充满着你们这种
who get
不用任何努力
everything easily
就可以轻易
without any effort!
得到一切的人
Not today.
今天不会了
Young Master Hua,
我的华二公子
haven't I told you before?
我不是跟你说过了吗
If it wasn't for your surname Hua,
如果不是因为你姓华
could you withstand
你经得起
my investigation?
我魏岱擎的调查
Not a chance!
你也配
Don't lump me
别再把我
together with the Hua family.
跟华家扯在一起
That's right.
这就对了
In this situation,
现在这个情况
even your father
就算是你父兄
and brother combined
加在一块儿
couldn't save you.
也救不了你
Who wins and who loses
谁输谁赢
is no longer something
已经不是你们华家
your Hua family can decide.
所能决定的了
[The newspaper sets its final print]
报社每天下午一点
[at one o'clock every afternoon,]
定版印刷
[so we must]
所以我们必须
[get the evidence earlier]
更早地拿到证据
[and bring it back.]
把它送回来
Even if I died here today,
即便我今天死在这里
you wouldn't win
你也赢不了
because you don't know
因为你根本不知道
what you're fighting for,
自己为了什么而拼命
nor do you understand
你也不知道
what faith and ideals are about.
什么是信仰与理想
You're just
你只是为了
climbing up the ladder
满足自己内心的虚荣
for your vanity,
为了所谓的名利
or so-called fame and fortune,
不择手段地往上爬
because you don't really know
因为你根本就不知道
what you want.
自己想要什么
I don't need to know
我不需要知道
But I know
可是我知道
that what I want most now
我现在最想要的就是
is to prove you're a communist!
证明你是共产党
I want to prove to everyone
我要向所有人证明
that I
我
was right from the very beginning.
从一开始就是对的
Prove to whom?
你向谁证明
To the Reviving Society
向安琪啤酒公司
behind A.G. Beer?
背后的复兴社证明吗
You don't really think
你不会真的以为
they had an interest in you, do you?
自己被复兴社看上了吧
Don't be naive.
别傻了
It's just a trap set by Hua Liang
那不过是华梁为了找我
to find me.
所设的一场圈套罢了
From beginning to end,
从头到尾
you were just a pawn.
你不过是一枚棋子
You're right.
你是对的
Captain,
队长
hold on.
你坚持住
Stay with me.
一定要坚持住
Don't fall asleep.
千万不能睡着
Captain,
队长
you said it,
你说过的
we're going to have a victory meeting.
我们要一起胜利会师
Promise me,
答应我
Captain,
队长
don't fall asleep!
别睡着